Um started off the day at 34 taking
Chase Basantis out of Texas A&M. Uh you
know throughout the day today had a lot
of uh a lot of phone calls. There was a
lot of interest in pick 34. Um you know
we had at you know different at
different times six seven eight teams
we're interested in coming up. Um you
know nothing uh nothing really came
close to getting us to move off that
pick. We're excited to add Chase. Um big
physical player out of&M played against
a lot of good people there. uh really in
practice blocking his own D lineman that
he had to block there for the last three
years and then in the SEC obviously high
level of uh competition. So excited to
add Chase. And then just now just a
little bit ago um at the top of the
third round um 65 um again had had a
little bit of trade interest, not as
much as 34. Um and then took Carson back
there at the the top of the third round.
So, you know, Carson uh has played a lot
of football, played, uh, you know,
two-year starter at Georgia, won a lot
of games there, had some success, uh,
and then, you know, obviously this year
goes down and and and has a heck of a
year for Miami. Uh, takes him to the the
national championship, saw him play out
here in the semi-finals, a Fiesta Bowl.
So, um, you know, excited to add those
two players and then, uh, we got, uh,
what, four picks coming up tomorrow
early in the fourth round. We'll kick it
off tomorrow morning. So, with that,
we'll open it up for you, with you guys.
What really sold you with Carson back?
>> Yeah, I think, you know, we spent a lot
of time with Carson. Um, you know, we
met with him at the combine. Um, brought
him in on a 30 visit. Um, you know,
there was no shortage of tape to
evaluate on Carson. Um, Carson's played
a lot of ball. Um, and so, you know,
banked a lot of reps. Um, you know, I
think really, uh, Carson's, uh, Carson
played in a lot of big game
environments. um played in a lot of
intense environments in um in the SEC,
those stadiums, those loud screaming,
wild, rabid fans of the SEC. Um and
then, you know, the the highest stage
that he could play on in the national
championship this year, all those
playoff games. Um you know, I think a
lot of things sold us sold us on Carson
and we were excited to add him to our
room.
>> What What did he show you in that in
that Fiesta Bowl game that you said you
were at? Obviously, when you're there in
person, I'm sure you could see it a
little bit differently. So, what did he
prove to you?
>> Yeah, really. I mean, there's no uh no
bigger opportunities than national
semi-final, you know, and so to be able
to answer the bell, lead his team, uh
bring him down there. It was a tight
game. Um you know, and so uh Carson's
been productive whole step of his way uh
a whole step of his career at different
spots and you know that that game was no
different.
>> How does how does him transferring from
Miami or from Georgia to Miami, how can
that help with his transition to to
year? Yeah, I think I think it's a great
transition because he's about to do
another one. So, he's going to have to
um you know, he picked up the G from the
Georgia program, goes to a new locker
room, has to you know, learn a new
offense, learn a new system, learn new
verbiage, learn a new building, and then
most importantly, learn new teammates.
And so, um he's about to do the same
thing here in a couple weeks when he
gets here. And, um so, it's, you know,
he's got a good practice run of it. Do
you see a scenario where Carson could
compete for a starting position or is
you know
>> Yeah, I you know I think like we just
announced his name about a half hour
ago. So, you know, I we just want to get
him in the building here and show him
where the cafeteria is and the locker
room is and and uh and get him fitted
for his gear and and then we'll we'll go
from there. We're excited to add be
great competition in that room and and
we'll see how it shakes out.
>> Mike made about his struggles when
pressured statistically. what made you
kind of willing to overlook that in
terms of his prospect profile?
>> I mean, you know, listen, hey, we we
look at everything with the player. Um,
you know, a lot has been made. I, you
know, I don't know. We we look at the
tape and and we evaluate him and his
performance and the guy's performed. The
guy's won a lot of games and we were we
were excited to add him.
>> What was it specifically about kind of
his skill set? I know you mentioned the
experience, but about his skill set that
kind of sold you on him.
>> Uh, he's big, he's tough, he's strong,
he's standing strong in the pocket. uh
not afraid to to take a hit in the
pocket. He's got a good good arm
strength. He can drive the ball down the
field. Um good accuracy, good
production. Um you know, those are all
things that we like.
>> To you, Mike,
>> what's it out to you with the back mic?
>> I think a lot of the things that Monty
was just saying. You know, he is a he's
a big solid dude, right? I mean, he's
6'4, he's 235 pounds. I mean, he looks
the part, right? And that that doesn't,
you know, mean that that's the end all
beall by any means. uh natural thrower
like he was just saying he's tough. I
think one of the coolest things about
him, especially spending some time with
them, um, you know, he's been through
those big games, but he's he's been
through some adversity, too, you know,
and, uh, and that's well documented, you
know, it's out there. And, um, I think
he's gotten better from it. You know, I
wasn't there, you know, through that
journey through the last few years, but,
uh, just being able to get to know him
and really spend some time. I really
enjoyed my time with him. I know Monty
did as well. I know our building did.
So, um, there's a lot of cool things
that, uh, we're excited about, you know,
working with him. [snorts]
>> With Chase, how does he fit into what
you guys want to do offensively?
>> Yeah. You want to go?
>> Go ahead. You got it.
>> Yeah. No. Um, Chase is is what you want
in a guard. He can move. He can cover
people up. Uh, but ultimately, he
strains to finish, you know, and that's
what you really like about him. Um, he's
willing to work. Justin Fry has known
him for a long time. He actually
recruited him. um obviously didn't pick
Justin, but uh uh at the time, but now
he has no choice. So, uh but no, they've
had a relationship for a long time.
Justin, um like I said, I mean, he's
he's known the guy, the person, where he
came from. Uh so, you think about just
the attributes I was talking about. You
think about the finish and then and then
the guy um good uh you know, good mix.
>> Envision him as a guard or he played
right tackle as a freshman. So, would
you move him over? He
>> he did and that's cool, right? I mean,
he had the the one year starting at
right tackle, then be able to move in
inside for the uh the last two yards or
two yards two years. Um, so I mean, you
see him in the inside, but I mean, you
know how it is in this league. Sometimes
you you don't got the choice, but yeah,
he'll be starting inside initially.
>> You expect him to start on the right
side with Isaac Sale on the left or or
still working through,
>> you know, it's still working through all
those kind of things because
particularly in again in the NFL with
the with the roster limits and then once
you obviously get down to game time. So,
um, you know, he'll he'll be on the
right side, he'll be on the left side,
and we'll figure out what the best five
are going to end up being. [snorts]
>> Monty, with all the changes that you've
made, all the additions you've made on
the offensive line, including Chase, do
you like how that position room is
trending right now?
>> I do. Yeah, I do. Whenever we can add
size, physicality, toughness, um,
competition. I mean, we've seen we've
seen what happens when when, uh,
attrition of the NFL season happens. So,
um, whenever we can add big physical
players up front, um, you know, we're
always going to take advantage of doing
that. with with Carson. He played a lot
of football, six years in college, 43
starts. Where could it help him kind of
slow down, sit for a little bit and
learn from the vets that you guys have
right now?
>> Yeah. Well, and he's had to do that in
his career, too, right? I mean, he was a
backup to a guy that I know really well
in Stson Bennett. Um, so yeah, I mean,
I, you know, it benefits anyone in any
position to be able to sit back.
Sometimes guys don't have the choice,
you know, because you have to put your
best 22 out on the field there, you
know. Um, so we'll see where this thing
all shakes out, but we're just excited,
like you said. I mean, just want to get
him here and show him his locker and get
to know his teammates and and and get
working from day one and we'll see where
it goes from there.
>> Monty, was it a priority for you
entering this draft at a quarterback?
>> Uh, priority? I mean, no, I don't think
so. Um, you know, you know, we've we've
talked about it. We never want to force
a pick. And, um, you know, ultimately at
65, uh, Carson was was a great fit for
us at that point. Um if if it wouldn't
have worked out then we would have went
on to the next guy.
>> You mentioned his big game experience
quite a bit. Where does that ring for
you in terms of when you evaluate a
player?
>> Yeah. I mean I think uh you know I think
uh when you when you see a player who
has had big game experience um you know
when they make this transition to the
NFL uh there's a little there's more
hope that it's not going to be too big
for him, right? So, it's not going to be
a deer in the headlights or I mean, you
know, the these guys have played that
have played at these high levels,
especially, you know, SEC um and then
into the ACC, these Big 10 programs,
like they're these stadiums are rocking
and they go into hostile environments
and so I think that's always good. I
mean, the NFL there's no bigger stage
and so I think the trans transition is a
little bit smoother for them.
>> You guys have not made a ton of moves uh
so far this offseason on the defensive
side of the ball. what kind of makes you
feel like that group can elevate uh kind
of from where it was last year to this
upcoming season with the lack of um
offseason investment so far? Yeah, I
mean I think you know with as we've
always talked I mean it's um whether
it's free agency or the draft like the
the fit has to match up and so um you
know it's it's you you have to it's a
balance of depending on young player
development uh to play depending on
players getting healthy. Um and then
also um you know like just like last
year when when we sat in here and we we
took all the uh all the defensive
players you know that wasn't that wasn't
a plan you know it's just how it worked
out. And so today we've gone and we
picked uh last two days we picked three
offensive players. That's just how it
worked out. So um you know I think we'll
we'll see what happens tomorrow. We got
four picks. Um but you know I think it's
it's a combination of what's available
whether it's free for agency or the
draft and then what meets with our the
resources that we have.
>> How does drafting Carson now affect your
approach with Jacobe?
>> Uh I don't think it really does. I think
it's completely independent. Um you know
excited to add Carson in. He's going to
have two veterans um to work with that
have played a lot of football. Um and
really I think those are two independent
things.
>> You guys rushing attack rank near the
bottom of the league last year and
obviously you talked about drafting best
player available whenever it comes to
it, but uh Jeremiah Love and then Bantis
like was it a cognizant effort by you
guys to try to improve the run game
heading to 2025? Donnie, yeah, I think
it was just a cognious effort to just
improve our team in general and, you
know, that that can look different and
uh it doesn't always, you know, like you
can have a plan, but then um where where
the draft lines up, it it you know,
that's where it takes you. And so, um I
think we're just always in in in the
lane of hey, we want to improve our
team, we want to add talent, we want to
improve competition. Um and the way it's
felt, it's just been on offense so far
the last two days. Um, Chase has not
allowed a sack for either one of you
guys in his last 18 games.
>> That's a That's good to hear, Josh. I
>> like that, man. That's Let's keep that
going. [laughter]
Person that goes through your head in
terms of your evaluation of a player
that
>> Yeah, he he's a tough dude. And I think
in both phases, um, you know, he has the
ability to get it done. And, you know,
kind of like we were just saying with
Carson, I mean, he's he's played some
pretty good football, too, right? you
know, at Texas A&M in the SEC going
against obviously a lot of good rushers,
whether it be interior or on the edge.
So, um, again, just just a guy that, uh,
excited to work with in terms of the
talent level, but again, the the the
toughness is really what sticks out to
me.
>> His athletic profile is pretty
impressive when you look at the speed
and strength. What can that do for an
offense? Kind of what
>> what does that enable you to do as a
play caller, I guess, especially? Yeah,
I mean it's, you know, you want guys
that can move, you know, whether it's
just in the protection and and the
slides and the man and and all that kind
of stuff, but particularly in the run
game can get connected at the second
level, but again, I don't think that's
just, you know, he's he's powerful
enough to reach a guy and anchor and
he's also, you know, u I would say has
the ability to get to the second level
and latch and and and drive, you know.
So, um, again, just just excited to get
working with them.
>> [snorts]
>> A lot of uh quarterbacks land in the
NFL. Sometimes it might not be a good
schematic for him. Obviously, you know
what you want to do, but we really
don't. What can you say about what
Carson Beck can fit inside like your
offense like specifically?
>> You know, it's it's cool cuz you can
evaluate his tape at Georgia and Miami,
all the things that we've been talking
about, the big game experience, all
those kind of things. But he's run what
you would say quote unquote an NFL style
system. you know, you watch the the
Miami National Championship game and you
have to see him clicking through
progressions against a really good
defense in Indiana, you know, so um for
him, you know, it's it's nothing against
any other quarterbacks. It's just he was
given the opportunity to kind of be in
more a similar system as to what most
NFL um you know, offenses do. I know you
said it wasn't necessarily intentional
to draft a quarterback, but when you've
got not just someone like Jacobe, but
Jacobe who's been in the league for 10
years and as as strong of a leader as he
is, does that give you maybe like
reassurance of knowing what as a rookie
Carson Beck who he's going to be sharing
that room with and learning from?
>> Yeah, I mean, Danny, I think like
absolutely. And I think we have a lot of
good veterans. I mean, you we've seen
some of our players have reached out to
us about when we when we take a player.
um people, our players have reached out
and congratulated our rookies already or
the guys that we've drafted already. And
you know, I think that's big for our
locker room in general, just having um
having veterans that are willing to
reach out and have it show the example
and show what it means to be a pro. Um
so, you know, our quarterback room, our
running back room, our O line room, they
all got three new players to work with
and I know they're going to embrace
those three.